影城时光影业
A24影业
探戈娱乐
高频娱乐
帕斯特尔公司
出品公司
A24影业
探戈娱乐
高频娱乐
大海滩公司
制作公司
帕斯特尔公司
字幕译制
蒙 太 奇 字 幕 组
天呐 你终于到了
Oh, my God! Hi!
我去 冷死我了
Fuck, it's fucking cold!
啊 啊 啊
Ahhh!
- 终于来了 - 终于来了
- You made it! - I made it!
我想死你了
I missed you!
- 天呐 我也想你 超想你 - 耶
- Oh, my God, I missed you, I missed you! - Yay!
搭把手 冷死我了
Help me, it's fucking cold!
你竟然还住在这儿
I cannot believe you still live here.
嗯 你每次都这么说
Yeah, well, you say that every time.
手都冻麻了 啊 该死的
I can't feel my fucking hands, ah! shit me.
我来拿吧 让我来拿
Let me take that. Let me take that.
可重了
It's really heavy.
是啊 重的要命
Yeah, fuck, it is heavy.
里面是给我带的礼物吗？
Did you bring me presents?
哦 不是 就一大堆袜子
Oh, no, just like eighteen pairs of socks.
这儿有的是袜子
I have socks.
是 但宝贝你的尺码太大了
Yeah, but your feet are huge, babe.
“宝贝”相伴的时光
可真重呀
It's really heavy.
天呐
Oh, my God.
- 我是这么想的 - 嗯
- This is what I think. - Yeah.
跟男人做爱的时候...
When you are having sex with a guy...
嗯
Yeah.
- 有时... - 嗯哼
- Sometimes... - Mhmm.
他们会突然冒出句...
They are saying stuff like,
“喜欢吧”
"You like that."
嗯？
Mhmm.
就知道你喜欢
You like that.
嗯 到底啥意思
Mhmm. What is that, even?
对
Right.
哦 懂了 太爹味了
Oh, that's deep.
我觉得 他们是说...
I think... I think they mean
说我喜欢...
you like...
- 那玩意儿 - 那玩意儿
- That. - That.
- 对 说你喜欢他的鸡鸡 - 那东西
- Yeah. "You like my dick." - Or that.
就好像 他们把那玩意儿当成是自己的一切
But it's like, they like, it's like, also their dick is their whole self.
“喜欢我的鸡鸡吧”等同于“喜欢我吧”
So they're like, "Do you like the dick? Do you like me?"
- “爱我吧” - 得了吧
- "Do you love me?" - "Do you love me!"
那意思是“用我的鸡鸡爱你”
"And I am fucking you with my dick."
对
Right.
那爱就像...
And sometimes it's like...
别
Don't.
或者像...
No, sometimes it's like...
天呐
Oh, God.
有时像...
Sometimes it's like...
像吧
Kinda.
- 可不是嘛 - 像这...
- No. It is. - It's like...
有时感觉自己灵魂出窍 从他眼里...
Sometimes it's like you leave your mind and you're like, seeing it from, like,
- 他的视角 - ...看自己
- perspective behind. - Inside their brain.
看自己屁股可怪了
Your butt looks weird.
有时还...对 哈哈
Sometimes it's like... right!
那我什么时候能看？
So, are you gonna let me read it?
别急 还没好呢
Yeah. But it's not done.
连正式稿都算不上
It's not even a proper draft.
但总归是个稿子
But it's a draft.
可不是嘛
It's definitely a draft.
还是那种纽约同性恋题材吗？
Is it still about gay New York stuff?
对 不过这次更黑暗 偏心理化 也很幽默
Yeah, but now it's, like, dark and like psychological, but also funny.
我绝对要看
I will need to read that.
【Ahoy源自17世纪海员打招呼】
啊嗨！
Ahoy!
他在跟我们说话吗？
Is that guy talking to us?
呃 他好像喊了句"啊嗨"
Ugh, I think he just said, "Ahoy."
啊嗨 邻居！
Ahoy there, neighbor!
啊嗨！
Ahoy!
唉 他占了我们的树
Ugh, he's in our spot.
天杀的
Fuckin' hell.
真想你还住在这儿
I wish you still lived here.
嗯
Yeah.
哪怕住近点
Or closer, at least.
嗯 我也想你搬去我那
Yeah, I wish you lived closer to me too.
不过我还是喜欢这儿
I like it here, though.
你确定？
Are you sure?
怎么了？
Why?
压力很大 对吧？
It's a lot, right?
待在这里的话
Still being here.
在哪儿都不轻松
Well, it's a lot to be wherever.
嗯 的确
Yeah. That's true.
研究生院真让人
School was like...
- 呃 让人作呕 - 呃
- Ugh, Grad school was... - Ugh.
没错
Exactly.
你结完婚还会想我吗？
Do you miss me even though you're married?
会呀 即便结了婚 还是会想你啊
Yes, I miss you even though I'm married.
都结婚了
Married.
- 哎 - 都变成大人了
- Ugh. - So grown up.
真变成大人了
It's so grown up.
嘿 嘿 那边的
Hey! Hey, you over there!
我结婚了
I'm married!
刚领过证了
I'm in a union that the state knows about!
我爸离婚了
My dad is divorced.
哦 真惨
Oh, that's sad.
没关系的
That's okay.
那么 我们现在怎么办？
Well, what do we do now?
【电影《十二怒汉》（1957）陪审员辩证真相与偏见】
就你一人了
You're alone.
我不管
I don't care whether I'm alone or not.
这是我的权利
It's my right.
对 是你的权利
It's your right.
你们想咋样 我就认定他有罪
What do you want? I say he's guilty.
讲讲你的理由
I wanna hear your arguments.
我说过我...
I gave you my...
【《洛丽塔》：纳博科夫（美籍俄裔）描绘未成年人性剥削的争议之作】
《洛丽塔》
真恶心
Ew.
《洛丽塔》
来了
Yes...
咦
Oh.
- 你好 - 你好
- Hi. - Hi.
- 有事吗？ - 呃 没 抱歉
- Can I help you? - Uh, no. I'm sorry.
我敲错门了吗？
Do I have the wrong house?
是这户没错啊
No. This is the right house.
- 你是... - 等下
- Are you... - Wait.
完了 完了
No. No.
哦 别 别 别
Oh, no. no, no, no, no.
就是这门啊
This is the house, yeah.
- 你找安尼丝吗？ - 对 是
- Are you looking for Agnes? - Yes, yeah.
盖文
Gavin!
- 你好呀 安尼丝 - 我是利迪
- Agnes. - Lydie.
哦 你就是利迪 真尴尬
Oh, you're Lydie. Oh, my God!
抱歉 因为周末又到了
Okay, I am so sorry, this is the weekend.
是啊
Yeah.
看来我错了
My mistake.
没事 盖文是我邻居
No problem. Gavin is my neighbor.
盖文 别忘了你住那边
Gavin, you actually live over there.
哦 对 我住那边
Oh, yes. I live there.
- 敲错了 - 没关系
- Oops. - That's okay.
做个好梦吧 盖文
Sweet dreams, Gavin.
愿上帝管管你这可怜的灵魂 拜拜
God bless your lost soul, and have a good night.
- 很高兴见到你 利迪 - 我也是
- It's nice to meet you, Lydie. - You too.
他真可爱
He's cute.
- 他？- 你找他来上床的
- Who? - You're fucking him.
不 才没有
No, I'm not.
- 把邻居找来上床的 - 不 没这事儿
- You're fucking your neighbor. - No, I'm not.
你想和邻居盖文上床
You're fucking your neighbor named Gavin.
是你想吧
You are.
才不是 才不是
I'm not. I'm not.
- 那我也没 - 你就是想
- No. I'm not. - You are fucking him.
- 才不想 - 你就是想和他上床
- I'm not. - You're fucking Gavin!
- 安尼丝 - 嗯
- Agnes. - Mhmm.
我得跟你说件事
I need to talk to you about something.
好
Okay.
嗯 是关于我身体的事
Okay. So it's about my body.
哦 你身材很棒
Oh, your body is perfect.
哦 谢谢
Oh, thank you.
但 呃 我不是那个意思
But, um, I didn't mean it like that.
好
Okay...
我肚子里有个宝宝
So I have a baby in me.
- 怀了？ - 是啊
- You do? - Yeah.
什么？现在就怀了吗？
What? Right now?
现在
Right now.
- 嗯 - 真假的
- Yeah. - What?!
天呐
Oh, my God.
天呐 你的身体真是个奇迹
Oh, my God. Your body is a miracle.
天呐
Oh, my God.
你紧张吗？
Are you scared?
嗯 有点
Yeah, yeah.
但也很开心吧？
Oh, but are you glad?
嗯 是呀 挺好的
Yeah, yes. It's good.
显然这是我想要的
Like, I wanted it, obviously.
费了好大劲
Like, we tried a million times.
对 你确实想要
Yeah. You did want it.
- 对 - 利迪
- Yeah. - Lydie...
打算用我的名字吗？
Are you gonna name it Agnes?
哦
Oh.
嗯 我不知道 我不确定
Yeah. I don't know. I don't know.
别急着拒绝
Try and think about it.
捐的精子质量肯定不错
So it must have been good sperm.
对啊 幸好如此
Yeah. Thank God for that
某个高个儿白人的好精子
random, tall white guy's good sperm.
要不我也用他的生个孩子
Maybe I should have his babies too
正好当兄弟
and then they can be brothers.
都是匿名的
Well, he's pretty hard to track down, so.
有照片嘛 能把他找出来
Well, we have his picture, so we could look him up.
能摸摸吗？
Can I touch it?
好啊
Yeah.
我什么都感觉不到
I don't really feel anything.
因为还没长成个小宝宝
That's because it's not like a baby yet.
多大了？
How old is it?
有十周吧
Ten weeks?
所以估计挺小的
So probably really small.
对
Yeah.
像老鼠那么大？
What, like a mouse maybe?
老鼠有多大来着？
How big is a mouse?
哦 比那还小
Oh, it's smaller than that.
哇 竟然比老鼠小
Wow, smaller than a mouse.
今晚可别跟任何人提这个
Don't tell anyone tonight about...
放心吧
Oh, don't worry.
我从不乱说秘密
I never tell secrets
除非我真想讲
unless I feel it is a secret I really wanna tell.
这话听着一点也不让人放心 宝贝
That is not reassuring, babe.
我真不想去
I don't wanna go.
不行
No!
不行 得去 不然娜塔莎会把我宰了
No, we have to. Natasha will kill me.
我觉得 她给人感觉态度不好
I feel like... I feel like she's, like, rude,
说话带刺
like, tonally.
可不是 她讲话可刺人了
Oh, she definitely has a very rude tone.
对吧
Right?
她说话语气真有问题
She's got a really rude tone.
你怕吗？
Are you afraid?
有点
Yeah.
是怕疼吗？
For the pain?
是啊
Yeah.
但这是个独立的人啊
But also because it's like, a person.
我想养出个好人
I wanna make a really good person.
你会把孩子带成好人的
You're gonna make a good person.
会疼得要命的
It's gonna hurt so bad.
可不是 会疼死你的
Oh, my God, it seems like it hurts so bad!
不 别这么说
No! Don't say that.
我能说
I'm allowed to say that,
不许你说
you're not allowed to say that.
废话不说
Blah, blah, blah. Doesn't matter.
简而言之 房子买到了
Short story is, we got the house,
但花的比我们预期多得多
but we had to pay, like, significantly more than we wanted to.
喜欢这房子吧？我家的！
Do you like this house? My house?
嗯 挺喜欢的
I, I do. Yeah. Oh, my God.
木头 好有质感
The wood... it's gorgeous.
高档的 很奢华
It's rich. Like dark.
嗯
Yeah.
准备搬哪些东西来？
What are you gonna put in it?
- 这房子？ - 对
- In our house? - Yeah.
嗯 那沙发
Uh... our couch,
那床
our bed,
本尼父母给她的五斗柜
Benny's parents' dresser.
什么都搬来
All your stuff.
对 没错
Yes. Exactly.
果然
That makes sense.
你现在真的长大了
You're like a fully fledged adult now.
大伙儿 我们有多久没聚了？
Guys, how long has it been since, like, we've hung out?
见面只能尴尬来句...
I'm just sort of like...
你好
Hi.
我们毕业有三年了吧？
Is it three years since we graduated?
- 四年了吧 - 哦 都四年了吗
- Four, I think. - Oh, my God, is it four years?
是啊
Yeah.
时光飞逝啊
Time really does fly.
时光真飞逝啊
不过 对我和安尼丝大概不算
But not for me or Agnes probably,
我们还待在学校里
since we're still here, still at the school.
你还待在那房子里
You're still at your same house.
那破房子里
That little house.
就你们三个走出去的会觉得飞逝
But time probably flies for the three of you who left.
- 去纽约啦 - 嗯 对 纽约
- New York. - Yeah, yeah. New York.
哦
Wow.
替你高兴
Good for you.
嗯 回来这趟感触挺深
Um, but it's a trip being back.
去安尼丝家路上路过学校
I drove past the campus on my way to Agnes',
见到图书馆就起鸡皮疙瘩
and I just got, like, full body chills when I saw the library.
那图书馆 利迪 别提了
The library. Lydie, no. please.
你懂吧
You know what I mean?
那地方给我留着很深的压力印记
I have, like, deeply ingrained stress from that place.
对 在研究院那会儿真太狠了
Yeah, Grad school was wild. I honestly feel like
我写那论文跟长征一样
I worked on that thesis for like, a decade.
可不是嘛 有次我在图书馆自习室
Yeah. This one time, um...on the third floor in a private room,
【《小杜丽》：狄更斯（英）刻画阶级与贫困的辛辣作品】
差点想用《小杜丽》那书把脸划破
I almost paper cut my face open with my copy of Little Dorrit
好去医院里睡个安稳觉
just so I could go to the hospital and have a good night's sleep.
没真做 但闪过那念头
I didn't do it, but I thought about it.
嗯 有时我做噩梦
Yeah, sometimes I have nightmares
梦到我论文全变白纸 我还把它吃了
where my thesis is like all blank pages, and then I eat the pages.
天呐 那好可悲
Oh, my God, that's so sad.
是啊 可不是嘛 真的挺可悲的
Yeah. It is really sad, huh.
那么 安尼丝 你就过得顺风顺水了？
So, Agnes, it was really that easy for you?
不想谈谈什么事情吗？
No story? Nothing to share?
那事儿可不是安尼丝的错 是德克尔太粘她
Well, it's not Agnes' fault that Decker liked her best.
对 不是她的错 说来我都生气
No, it wasn't her fault,  but, um, it pissed me off.
这鱼做的不错 里面放了什么？
This fish is amazing. What's... what's in it?
鱼啊
Fish.
你们俩近况如何？
Uh... well, how is it, you two?
都是老师了
You're the teachers now.
我还没有转正
I am still part time,
不过下学期会让我带一门课吧
but I think I'm gonna teach a class next semester...
还没正式说 但挺有戏
which they haven't said is what's gonna happen, but it could.
- 是啊 挺有戏 - 不 是一定会
- Yeah, it could. - No. It will.
对 对 一定会
Yeah. Yes. It, it will.
我们英语系这边还有新情况
Well, we have news in the English department.
安尼丝 该你的大新闻了
Agnes? Agnes has big news.
去下洗手间 抱歉
Bathroom. Sorry.
安尼丝已转正 占了威尔金森留的位置
Agnes is now a full-time teacher. She took Wilkinson's spot.
是接手了 那位置
Filled the spot.
安尼丝真厉害 这么年轻就转正了
Agnes is like super young to be full-time faculty.
对 五十年来最年轻的 靠腿上位的
Yeah, she's like the youngest in fifty years, that bitch.
开玩笑啦
I'm kidding.
没去干净
There's a bone.
什么？
What?
【西餐通常会把鱼刺和骨头去除后上桌】
鱼刺没去干净
In the fish.
你这鱼没剔干净 里面还有根鱼刺
There's, like, a bone in the fish that you served me.
抱歉
Sorry.
没事 没事
No, it's... it's fine.
下次你招待客人
It's just like maybe you should, like,
把鱼刺处理好 注意点礼数
debone it a little bit better before you serve it to people.
你好呀 我的猫宝贝
Hello, my baby.
我的猫宝贝
Oh, you're a baby.
妈妈爱你 妈妈爱你
I love you. I love you.
噢 要下去吗？
Oh, you wanna get down?
好 把你放下去
Okay. I'll put you down.
你会走出这房子吧？
You leave the house, right?
嗯 天天走出啊
Yeah. I leave the house.
得去上班 我有工作的 利迪
I go to work. I have a job, Lydie.
但...
But...
你还待在那间办公室里啊
you're still in the same office.
的确
Yes.
安尼丝 你说过你会换办公室的
Agnes, you said that you were gonna switch.
我 我可不想被迫解释为什么换
Well, I...I didn't wanna have to explain why it's weird for me to be in that office.
编个理由 说墙发霉之类的
Maybe you should say there's mold or something.
也许吧
Maybe.
该死 要我举报说墙里有死动物发臭吗？
Do you want me to call them and say there's a dead animal in the wall?
你真是大好人 但不用
You are an angel from heaven, but no.
我刚转正
It's like, I just got the job.
我都不知道我配不配得上这位子
I don't even know if I should have the job.
安尼丝 别这样
Agnes.
我不想嫌我的办公室
I don't wanna complain about my office,
空间大 采光又好
which is technically huge, and there's a lot of light,
我能明白他为什么喜欢这间
and I can see why he liked it.
总之 是的 我决定走出去这房子
Anyways, yes, I leave the house.
安尼丝...
Agnes...
别...
don't...
去死
die.
我不会死的
I'm not gonna die.
要真打算自尽
If I was gonna kill myself,
我早在去年做了
I would have done it like last year...
或者在前年
or the year before.
呃 肯定在前年
Ugh. Or, like, definitely the year before.
安尼丝 别
Agnes.
我不会死的
No. I'm not gonna die.
那我也回敬你一句
Let me return the sentiment.
你也别想着去死
You please don't die.
利迪...
Lydie...
你怀了个小宝宝
You're having a little baby.
对
I know.
你会把宝宝照顾得很好
You're gonna take such good care of your little baby.
我不会死的
I won't die.
求你别死
Please don't die.
不 我求你
No, you please don't die.
想跟宝宝打个招呼吗？
Do you wanna say hello?
嗨
Hi.
我是安尼丝
I'm Agnes.
我是你妈咪
I'm your mommy.
利迪和弗兰可能会有别的说法 但听我说
Lydie and Fran may tell you otherwise, but heed my words.
- 我是你妈 - 安尼丝！
- I'm your mother. - Agnes!
- 别闹 正经点 - 好 好吧
- Do it properly. - Yeah. All right.
嗨 我是安尼丝
Hi. I'm Agnes.
我不是你妈咪
I'm not your mommy.
我就是你妈咪
I am your mommy.
哎 真受不了你
Oh, for goodness sake.
我觉得宝宝踢我了
I felt it kick.
没有 你没有
No, you didn't.
那包...多谢
Are you gonna... Thank you.
别走
Don't go.
来
Hey.
我很快就来看你
I'll see you soon.
什么时候？
When?
来纽约吧
Come to New York.
我有空床
I've got an extra bed.
【TA为中性代词】
跟弗兰说我讨厌TA
Tell Fran that I hate them.
才不
No.
好吧 其实不讨厌TA
No, I don't hate them.
我知道 宝贝
I know, babe.
- 爱你 - 也爱你
- Love you. - Love you.
哦 等下
Um, no.
快点回来哦
Come soon.
不是因为...
Not because of, like,
不是因为我要去死之类的 只是...
not because I'm gonna kill myself, but just...
只是...
Just...
别拖那么久才回来
don't wait so long to come back.
好的
Okay.
好
那桩噩事的时光
靠！
Fuck!
怎么回事？
What is happening?
- 到底怎么了？ - 靠！天呐！
- What's happening? - Oh, my God!
我受够学校了！
I hate school!
学校真把人逼疯了！
School fucking sucks!
我脑袋像着了火
My brain feels like it's on fire.
像快要死了一样！
Like I'm gonna fucking die!
我才发现 宝贝
I just realized, babe,
【泰德·休斯：英国诗人 以强烈自然意象和原始神话力量著称】
没人会在乎泰德·休斯
no one gives a fuck about Ted Hughes.
不对 大家都挺在乎泰德·休斯的
No, everyone cares about Ted Hughes.
不 不 不 我不相信
No, no, no. I can't believe this.
我花了两年研究那男人
I spent two years writing about a guy.
现在和男人上床我都不睁眼
I don't even fuck guys with my eyes open anymore.
只想闭眼想女人
I just close my eyes and imagine women.
要展开说说吗？
Do you wanna talk about that?
说什么？
About what?
没什么
Nothing.
好了 我来了 抱歉 来晚了
Okay, I'm here. Sorry, I'm here.
都写完了吗？
Did we do it?
勉强
Barely.
- 德文 你呢？ - 我做完了
- Devin? - Yes, I did.
抱歉各位 我平时不爱拖延
I am so sorry. I don't really procrastinate,
不是故意抢先的
so this wasn't like a whole thing for me.
没事的
That's okay.
别太谦虚 真金藏不住的
Keep showing off, it'll get you places.
利迪
Lydie.
我在这儿
I'm Lydie.
你写好了吗？
Did you finish?
呃 是的 嗯...
Uh, yeah, um...
好吧 是这样的
Yeah, but the thing is,
别生气 确实写完了
like, don't be mad. I did finish it.
只是最后一页是从...
The last page is, like, a copy and paste extract of...
【《向伯利恒跋涉》：琼·狄迪恩（美）散文 描绘60年代旧金山嬉皮与反文化】
从《向伯利恒跋涉》复制来的 不是我写的
"Slouching Towards Bethlehem" that I didn't write.
【耶茨：指关注家庭生活的小说家理查德·耶茨（美）】
- 抄耶茨还是狄迪恩？ - 是狄迪恩
- Yates or Didion? - Didion.
当然是狄迪恩
Always Didion.
嗯...你看
Uh... Hey, you know what?
我是你的导师 帮手 之类的
I'm supposed to be your mentor, helper, whatever.
来这是帮你按时交论文的
I'm just here to make sure it happens.
我的写完了
I did mine.
行 好 不错 娜塔莎
Okay. Good. That's... that's great, Natasha.
利迪 周三前能搞定吗？
Lydie, you think you can finish by Wednesday?
去掉狄迪恩的稿子给我
Get me your draft minus the Joan by then?
嗯 行吧
Yeah, again...
抱歉打断
Sorry about that.
要看我的吗？
Are you gonna read mine?
要啊 职责所在嘛
Of course. That's my job.
你还要问安尼丝她交了吗？
Are you gonna ask Agnes if she did hers?
要
Yeah.
安尼丝...
Agnes...
进展如何？
How'd yours go?
挺好 做完了
Fine. I did it.
等不及想看了
Can't wait to read.
你也会想看我那份吧？
But you're gonna read mine too though, right?
会的
Yes.
【《反对阐释》：苏珊·桑塔格（美）散文 批判过度理论化 主张直接感受艺术】
《反对阐释》
我怎么还在写这东西？
Why am I still working on this?
因为你还没写完
Because you didn't finish it.
别介意
No offense.
别显摆了
Stop bragging.
我又没显摆
I'm not bragging.
你腿翘在墙上呢
Your legs are on the wall.
那又怎样？
So?
要是我也写完了
Well, if I'd finished it,
我腿也会翘上墙的
my legs would be on the wall too,
可我还没写完
but I haven't.
所以我没翘着
So, my legs aren't on the wall.
行 我把腿放下
Okay. I will take them down.
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
教授
普雷斯顿·德克尔
这写得真出类拔萃
又怎么了？
What?
你应该跟他上床
You should fuck him.
我不想跟他上床
I don't wanna fuck him.
- 真的？ - 真的
- Really? - Yes.
那如果你不想 就千万别做
Well, if you don't wanna fuck him, definitely don't fuck him.
不会的
I won't.
我觉得他想上你
I think he wants to fuck you.
真的？
Really?
嗯
Yeah.
哦 这可不妙
Well, that sucks.
怎么了？
Why?
他老夸我聪明是图这个吗？
Do you think that's why he's telling me I'm smart?
不 我觉得他夸你因为你真很聪明
No, I think he's telling you you're smart because you're really smart.
好
Okay.
你会怎么回他...
What would you say though...
他开口要你跟他睡？
if he asked you to fuck him?
我会说不的
I would say no.
他要开口 我会生气的
I would be upset if he asked.
懂了
I get that.
我会当面说 不...
I would say no...
不过 谢谢你
but thank you.
教授 普雷斯顿·德克尔
英语系
请进
Come on in.
嗨
Hi.
安尼丝 你好
Agnes, hi.
谢谢你见我
Thanks for meeting with me.
也谢谢你来见我
手头挺忙的？
Are you working on something?
我是说...
I mean...
没有 没什么
No. Not, not...
没什么特别的
not really.
好吧 你得交代清楚
Well, now you have to tell me.
为什么？
Why?
因为我已经知道不少了
Because now I know too much.
嗯 行 好吧
Uh, yeah, okay. Um...
我在写本书
I'm writing a book.
- 书？ - 嗯
- A book? - A book.
大部头吗？
A long book?
- 中等长度 - 挺好
- Medium. - Good.
为啥？
Why?
长篇就那样 说得太透
Well, long is like... okay, we get it.
对 短篇则...
Right. And short is like...
像雾里看花
Why did you even write a book?
嗯 我写的这中篇则...
Yeah, well, even though this is medium...
- 正好合适 - 嗯
- The perfect length. - Yeah.
这书烂透了 看见它我都想上吊
I have to say it is horrible, and every time I look at it, I wanna kill myself.
就需要坏书来衬托
Well, there actually have to be books like that
好书才能更显珍贵
so that we can distinguish which books are really the good books.
对
Yes.
这破书也算是为社会做贡献了
I'm doing a public service by writing a shit book.
好吧
Well,
这样安慰你吧
if it helps at all,
我挺喜欢你第一本小说的
I liked your first novel.
它烂得独特
I liked how fucked up it was and...
让我觉得活着有意义
how it made me feel like there's a reason,
哪怕我看不清那理由
even if I can't see it, that I'm alive.
读起来不像小说
And it didn't feel like fiction,
不是那种做作的虚构
which I think is a compliment in this case.
我 我做别的事时常想起它
And...I think about it all the time when I'm doing other stuff,
吃冰淇时 望窗外时
like eating ice cream or looking out the window.
谢谢你
Thank you.
也谢谢你
好...
Okay, uh...
别光说我了
Enough about me.
你的论文我看完了
I read your thesis.
看得挺快的
You read it really fast.
是啊 嗯...
Yeah, well, I, uh...
真的爱不释手
to be honest, I couldn't put it down.
谁把你手粘上面了吗？
Someone glue your hands to it?
啥？
What?
噢
Oh...
抱歉 玩笑开得有点莫名
I'm sorry. Makes basically no sense.
不 挺有趣的
No, it does.
嗯
Yeah.
- 总之... - 嗯
- Anyway, so, uh... - Yeah.
从第三页到第七页这段
This whole section from page three through seven,
简直
I find to be absolutely just...
出类拔萃
extraordinary.
真的
Really.
抱歉
Sorry.
抱歉 我前妻是个检察官 这就...
Sorry, my ex is a prosecutor, which...
哇 搞法律的
Oh, wow, the law.
对 我前妻...
Yeah. My ex- wife...
特爱法律
loves the law.
她在出庭 我孩子病了 我得...
She's in court, my kid's sick. I have to...
我得赶紧走了
I've gotta run.
- 该死 抱歉 - 没事的
- Fuck, sorry. - Oh, that's okay.
你配得上我全部注意力 这论文也是
You should have my full attention, and frankly, this paper deserves that.
- 我们改天再约 - 行 可以
- We can reschedule for later. - Yeah, that's fine.
好 我得走了 回来给你发短信
All right, I gotta... I'll text you.
- 好 - 我 呃...
- Okay. - I'll, uh...
抱歉这么仓促
Sorry I have to run like this.
- 哦 没关系 - 哦 等下
- Oh, that's okay. - Oh, actually,
你得看看这个
you should look at this.
我刚收到的
I just got it.
【《到灯塔去》：伍尔夫（英）1927年所著意识流小说 讲家庭、记忆和时间】
《到灯塔去》初版
First edition To The Lighthouse.
哇 谢谢
Wow, wow. Thank you.
嗯
Yeah.
能摸摸吗？
Can I touch it?
- 当然 - 好
- Yeah. - Okay.
就这样
All right.
思考一下
We are asked to reckon with the idea
结束生命 从肉身飞走
that taking his life, taking flight from the corporeal existence,
【莫里森（美）小说《所罗门之歌》 讲述黑人家庭的寻根与自由】
对奶娃来说
is perhaps for Milkman
是一种升华而非悲剧
a transcendence and not a tragedy.
他感觉自由与回归
Milkman feels he is returning to his ancestral home.
教授  普雷斯顿·德克尔
英语系
- 安尼丝 - 嗨
- Agnes. - Hi.
好 行 呃....
Great. Okay. Uh...
谢谢能临时赶来
Thanks for coming last minute.
抱歉约在我家 希望你不介意
Sorry, it's my house. hope that's okay.
嗯嗯 没事的
Yeah, yeah, no problem.
别担心 我...
Don't worry, my...
我孩子跟前妻在一起了
my kid's with my ex.
没关系的
It's all good.
- 来 进来 - 嗯
- Uh, come on in. - Okay.
哦 介意把鞋脱一下吗？
Oh, do you mind taking your boots off?
哦 对 我真笨
Oh, yeah. duh.
别
No.
- 抱歉 - 不用道歉
- Sorry. - Don't be sorry.
你带我的论文了吗？
Do you have my thesis?
哦 有的 有的 带了
Oh, yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
你鞋带开了
Your shoes are untied.
唔
Ooh.
我等得心都痒死了
Hey, I've been literally waiting with bated breath.
快说说
How did it go?
安尼丝 你没事吧？
Agnes, are you okay?
发生什么事了？
What happened?
说不上来
I don't know.
裤子被弄坏了
My pants are broken.
然后我们开始接吻
And then we started kissing.
我心想 我们竟然在接吻
And I thought, we're kissing.
我一直在想
I was thinking we were kissing the whole time,
这种接吻很糟
like in a bad way
一点也不享受
where you aren't having a good time,
就像被别人嘴顶着
and it's just like someone's mouth.
我跟他说 “我还没准备好亲...
And then I said, "I don't really think I'm ready to be kissing.
我刚结束一段恋情”
I just got out of a thing."
这是当时瞎编的
Which is something I made up.
找个借口是对的
It's okay to lie about that.
他回了句 “没事”
And then he said, "That's okay."
“在沙发上一起看个电影吧”
"We can just sit on the couch and watch a movie."
他播了个片子
So he started playing something.
是动画片 起初觉得怪怪的
It was animated, which I thought was weird.
但一想他还有个孩子
But then I remembered he has a kid,
就不那么怪了
so that made it less weird.
然后他把手伸到我裤裆上
Then he started putting his hand on my pants,
我想推开
and I was kinda moving it away.
他老是伸回来
But he kept moving it back to my pants,
最后直接把手伸到我裤子里
and then he started putting his hand down my pants, like,
就隔着层内裤
in between the pants and my underwear.
我不断扭身挣扎
And I was kinda squirming my body like...
他的...
he was...
他的手指粗暴使劲
his fingers were really strong and hard, like, in the bad way.
太用力了
Like, it was too hard.
要是我同意 可能会享受
Maybe it would've felt good if I wanted his fingers to be doing that.
但你不同意
But you didn't want that.
不 根本不同意
No, I didn't.
然后我拽出他的手 因为...
And then, I pulled his hand out because...
因为真不舒服
it didn't feel good,
甚至还疼
and it actually hurt, kinda.
然后我去吻他
And then I started kissing him
我心想
because I thought,
得做点什么
"Well, if we have to be doing something,"
宁可接吻也不想被摸
"I'd rather it be kissing than his fingers down there."
之后一片空白
And then I don't remember.
突然间 他又把手伸进来了
And then at some point, his hand was back in my underwear.
但这次是内裤里面
But under the underwear now.
我不断拽他的手
And I was trying to move it away again.
听上去你一直在想办法
Sounds like you were trying to move it away a lot.
嗯 一直在想
Yeah. That's what I kept thinking.
心想 只要再制止他一次
Like, one more time and he won't move it back
他就会明白
because it's so obvious I'm moving it away.
但他还不断地把手伸回来
But he kept moving it back.
然后...
And then...
他开始脱我裤子 用力扯
he was pulling down my pants. well, he was trying to pull them down,
但没解扣子
but they have a button.
他就一直扯啊扯
So he was pulling, pulling.
我就往回拽
And I was pulling them back up.
最后裤子被扯到大腿间
And then they were halfway down.
然后感觉有什么就 就进来了
And I felt something go in, like, in me,
我毛骨悚然
and my spine got cold.
我伸手去摸...
And I reached down to feel it and...
发现...
It was...
是他的...懂吧
It was him... you know?
然后我跳起来
And then I jumped up and...
坐到沙发另一头
I sat on the side of the couch.
不知道发呆了多久
I don't know how long.
只敢瞥他一眼
And I looked at his face once,
他居然 害怕了
and it was, like, scared.
- 他看起来害怕？ - 是
- His face was scared? - Yes.
然后我慢慢起身
And then I just got up kinda slowly,
拿上鞋
and I grabbed my boots,
开车回家
and I drove home,
然后就在这儿了
and now I'm here.
你说的就是...
That sounds like...
那种事
that.
就是...
That is...
那种事
that's the thing.
我真的 真的很心痛
I'm really, really sorry.
这检查是不是得一丝不挂？
I never know if I'm supposed to get fully naked.
- 只穿这病号服吗？ - 嗯
- Like in the gown? - Yeah.
- 你现在光着了吗？ - 是的
- Are you naked right now? - Yes.
小宝 你不该光着啊
Dude, I don't think you're supposed to be naked.
你好 是安尼丝吧？
Hi. You're Agnes?
- 嗯 你好 - 我是埃文斯医生
- Yeah, hi. - I'm doctor Evans.
被人性侵了？
You were sexually assaulted?
呃 是的
Uh, yeah.
现在感觉安全吗？
Do you feel safe now?
抱歉 开始前 额...我得说
Sorry, before... uh, we do that,
我可光着呢
I just want you to know that I'm fully naked.
- 啥？ - 是病号服下面光着 行吗？
- What? - Under the robe. Is that okay?
可以 没问题
Yeah. That's fine.
- 介意让下吗？ - 好 行
- Do you mind? - Yeah, sure.
好 什么时候的事儿？
So, when did this happen?
那件事？
The thing?
你受害
The assault.
昨天晚上
Last night.
昨天下午
Last evening.
昨天傍晚
Yesterday evening.
- 事后有洗澡吗？ - 洗了
- And have you showered? - I took a bath.
这种事最好...
So it's usually best to go to the emergency room
事发后马上来急诊
right after something like this happens.
行 下回记住了
Oh, okay. I will definitely keep that in mind for the next time.
在急诊室会用性侵取证包
Well, that's when we would use a sexual assault forensic evidence kit.
打断下 麻烦您换个说法
Oh, okay. I feel like you just need to...tonally shift away from the tone
换个语气
you're taking right now.
温和点那种
Like, we just need a tonal shift.
就想检查有没有被传到什么 通过阴道的那种
Just wanna make sure he didn't give me anything, like, vaginally or yeah.
施暴者在你体内射精了吗？
Did your attacker ejaculate in you?
额 我不太想叫他施暴者
Um, well, I wouldn't call him my attacker.
不是 啪 那种
It wasn't like, bah!
你可被强奸了啊
But you were raped.
- 哎呦喂 - 是 无言以对
- Whoa. - Yeah. And well put.
我理解你说不出口
I know this is hard to talk about.
不像是您真理解了啊
It doesn't feel that you know that.
没办法 得按流程里的问
These questions are protocol.
嗯 但您问TA的方式真尖锐啊
Yeah, you're asking them in a really freaky way.
冷静点 女士
Calm down, ma'am.
- 她很冷静 - 我可冷了
- Oh, she's calm. - I'm calm.
继续问吧
You can finish your questions.
他有没有在你体内射精？
Did he ejaculate in you?
真能问啊
Horrible word.
没 他进来的时间不长 就像...
No, the actual him being inside me part wasn't that long, it was like...
- 那几下 - 好
- that long. - Okay.
接下来抽个血 查怀孕
So, we'll do a blood test to check you for pregnancy
查性病感染
and sexually transmitted infections,
再来个宫颈培养
and then we'll do a cervix culture.
- 好享受啊 - 说啥？
- Yum. - Excuse me?
她说好享受啊
She said yum.
我马上回来 马上开始
I'll be right back, and we can get started.
- 安尼丝 - 嗯哼
- Agnes? - Mhmm.
他走了
He's leaving.
谁？
Who?
德克尔搬走了
Decker's transferring.
他在纽约上州找了个工作
He got a job in New York. Upstate.
他走了
He's leaving.
靠
Fuck.
什么鬼？
What the fuck?
是好事吗？
Is this good?
不是
No.
也许 说不准
Maybe. I don't know.
他跟你提过要走吗？
Did he say anything about this?
没
No.
昨天他桌上和平常一样乱
And yesterday his desk was, like, really cluttered.
不像要搬家的样子
Like he wasn't packed or anything.
所以他跑路了
So he's running.
挨千刀的
Fuck.
- 你好 我是... - 是安尼丝吧
- Hi, I'm... - Agnes.
你好 我叫伊丽莎白 这位是克莱尔
Hi, I'm Elizabeth. This is Claire.
- 你好 我是克莱尔 - 幸会
- Hi, Agnes. I'm Claire. - Hi.
能麻烦你跟我们来一下吗？
Do you mind coming back with us?
行
Sure.
很抱歉发生了这种事
We are so sorry to hear this happened to you.
我们会...
We are taking this
认真严肃处理的
really seriously.
怎么处理？
Are you gonna do anything?
我们会展开调查
We would begin an investigation.
只是你可能听说了
But as you may have heard,
他昨天递交了辞呈 在...
he sent in his letter of resignation yesterday at...
昨天下午4:18分
4:18 p.m.
而你是在今天早上8:42分才报告的
And you reported this today at 8:42 am.
好
Okay.
遗憾地是 他已经离职
Unfortunately, he's no longer under our employ.
因此无法实施
So we can't take the measures that we would normally take
停职 解雇之类的处分
such as suspending him or letting him go or...
无能为力
things of that nature.
这件事真不好办
These things are really hard,
很遗憾大学这边
and the University is unfortunately unable
无法承担任何责任
to take any kind of responsibility.
可他是我的导师啊
But he was my advisor.
前任 导师
Former advisor.
建议你去警局报案
You have the option of going to the police station and reporting this
让他们发逮捕令
and issuing an arrest warrant.
我们对此感同身受
We know what you're going through.
我们也是女性
We are women.
什么？
What?
我们也是女性
We are women.
嘿
Hi.
嗨
你是我邻居吧？
You're my neighbor, right?
嗯 我住这儿
Yeah, I live here.
你叫什么？
What's your name?
哦 呃 盖文
Oh, uh, Gavin.
盖文 幸会
Gavin, nice to meet you.
- 彼此彼此 - 我是安尼丝
- You too. - I'm Agnes.
【译注 开玩笑说安尼丝是耶稣化身】
圣经里的羔羊
Lamb of God.
- 什么？ - 算了
- What? - That's nothing.
没什么 我就是 呃...
It's all good, I'm just, uh...
你今晚忙啥？
What are you up to this fine evening?
呃 你有能点火的东西吗？
Oh, I was wondering, do you have, like, stuff that makes a fire?
哦 呃...
Oh, um...
火柴吗？
Matches?
不是 要那种助燃液 有吧
No, like a liquid. Is that a thing?
有的
Oh, yes.
- 烧烤助燃油 - 对 有吗？
- Lighter fluid. - Yes. Do you have that?
有
Yes.
用来干嘛？
Why do you need it?
呃 我跟一帮朋友要做烤肠
Um, my friends and I, we're gonna make, like, hot dogs.
哦 我也喜欢吃烤肠
Oh, hot dog sounds good.
抱歉 只买了两根
Oh, I'm sorry, we only bought two hot dogs.
哦 不 没关系 我...我跟我妈吃
Oh, no, that's no problem, I'm...I have dinner plans with my mom.
不是的
That's not true.
我怕被拒
I'm sorry, I just wanted to close myself off
才装作有事的
from the possibility of being rejected.
没事
That's no problem.
- 我去拿助燃油 - 好
- I'll get the lighter fluid. - Okay.
屋里暖和 进来坐坐？
Do you wanna come inside while I look?
算了 想在这儿等 行吗？
Uh, no, sorry. Can I wait outside?
行 没问题 我马上给你
Yeah. Don't worry about it. Um, I'll be back soon.
这该够用
This should do the trick.
太好了 谢谢
Great, thanks.
倒在要烧的东西上 就行了吧？
And so do I just pour this on the thing I want to be on fire?
烧什么 烧烤吗？
On the barbecue?
对
Yes.
呃 嗯 别倒太多
Uh, yeah, don't put too much of it on there.
好
Okay.
要 要我帮忙吗？
Do you... do you want my help?
不用
No.
谢谢你...
Thank you...
是盖文
Gavin.
对 盖文 真谢谢你 盖文
Gavin. Yes. Thank you, definitely, Gavin.
你不是住那边吗？
Uh, don't you live over there?
啥 哦 对 确实是 哈哈
Ha! Yup, I... yup, definitely. Oops.
【《乔凡尼的房间》：詹姆斯·鲍德温（美）所著小说 聚焦同性恋身份与孤独】
乔凡尼的房间
从哪儿弄的？
Why do you have that?
找邻居要的
I got it from the neighbor.
干嘛要？
Why?
肯定不是正常人会有的想法
It's definitely not, like, a good or normal train of thought.
好
Okay.
我本来想把德克尔办公室烧掉
I think I was gonna light Decker's office on fire.
好
Okay...
你真想这么做吗
Do you still wanna do it?
没想好
I don't know.
那我来做
I will do it.
你真好
That's really nice.
但不用
But no.
认真说 要是你想烧他办公室
No, seriously. If you need someone to burn his office down,
又不想自己去 我替你做
but you don't wanna do it yourself, I will do it.
不 我甚至不想咒他死
No, I don't even want him to die.
我想
I do.
我不想他死
I don't want him to die.
好吧 改主意了就告诉我
Well, if you change your mind...
谢谢
Thanks.
也许一起烧点小的
Maybe we could burn something smaller,
他头发或他笔之类的
like his hair or his pens or something.
我会考虑的
I'll think about that.
好
Okay.
哎 还得去做烤肠
I have to make hot dogs.
为嘛？
Oh, why?
我跟邻居编了大谎 不烤心里过不去
I told the neighbor, it's like this whole big lie. I'm stuck in a lie.
好 我来做
Okay. I will do it.
对不起
I'm sorry.
没事 我本想砍个人 相比这小菜一碟
No, it's fine. I was gonna, like, kill a man, so this is much easier.
家里有烤肠吗？
Do we have hot dogs?
不知道
I don't know.
嗨
Hi.
好 我要去买咖啡
Okay. I'm going to get coffee.
我能抱你吗？
Do you want me to pick you up?
哦 天呐
Well, fuck.
太美好了
This is really nice.
我想...
I guess um...
对 我爱你
Yup. I love you.
愿意陪我买咖啡吗？
You wanna come get coffee?
三文鱼罐头？
Salmon.
好吧 挺挑食的 有品位
All right, you're picky, an excellent quality.
金枪鱼的？
Tuna.
可能隔着罐头闻不出来
Maybe you're just smelling the can.
里面是金枪鱼
There's tuna inside.
好 各买一罐
All right, one of each.
嗨
Hey.
就这些吗？
Is this all for you today?
是的 麻烦了
Yes, thank you.
你带猫进来了吗？
Did you bring a cat into the grocery store?
没有啦
No.
就有
Yes, you did.
信号不好 说啥？
What did you say?
你骗人
You're lying.
不 才没呢
No, I'm not.
您的猫粮 谢谢惠顾
Here's your cat food.
咖啡没了
We ran out of coffee.
我买了
I got some.
我捡了只猫
I got a cat.
挺你啦
Whatever you need.
善问 恶问与自问的时光
谢谢大家来履行陪审员传召
Thank you for being here and completing your summons.
还没填的 不清楚流程的
For those of you who haven't done this and don't know what to expect,
请上前来领问卷表
please come up and get a questionnaire.
填好交回来
Fill it out and return it to us completed.
要用笔的话 请来拿
We have little pencils if you need a little pencil.
陪审员资格问卷表
姓名：安尼丝·沃德
年龄：28岁
【自我认同性别流动 非二元 偏女性】
陪审员资格问卷表
性别
女性
<——>
中性
以下人员免除陪审义务
The following jurors are dismissed.
陪审员 1号 3号 5号
Juror one, three, five,
7号 8号
seven, eight,
30号 32号
30, 32,
39号 25号
39, 25,
42号 43号
42, 43,
49号 59号
49, 59.
你们免除义务
You are dismissed.
谢谢 你们可以离庭了
Thank you. You can go.
富勒女士 通过刚才讲解
And do you think, Mrs. Fuller, based on that definition,
【证据使陪审员对被告有罪的怀疑不再合理】
您明白“排除合理怀疑”意思吗？
you understand the meaning of beyond a reasonable doubt?
明白
Yes.
要达到不怀疑的标准
That to be convinced beyond a shadow of a doubt,
在案发时非得亲眼见到吗？
you must have been there and seen the crime with your own eyes?
不用 明白
Yes. I understand.
大家都能以
And do the rest of you feel
- “排除合理怀疑”作为评判依据吗？ - 是
- you can apply that idea, beyond a reasonable doubt, to this case? - Mhmm
有多少人是父母？
How many of you have children?
沃瓜德先生 有孩子？
Uh, Mr. Woguard. You have a child?
嗯 是 索菲刚满四岁
Uh, yes. Soph just turned four.
假设您女儿在公园
Say you and your daughter were at the park
玩攀爬架
and she's playing on the monkey bars.
您有几分钟没看她
And you turned your back for a few minutes,
她跑过来说胳膊伤了
and then she runs over to you with a broken arm.
您怎么判断？
What would you think happened?
她从攀爬架上掉下来摔的
She fell off the monkey bars and broke her arm.
对 这就是间接证据的例子
Yes, so that's an example of circumstantial evidence.
根据事实可以做出的合理推断
That's what you can reasonably infer based on the facts that you have.
沃瓜德先生 能明白吗
Does this make sense, Mr. Woguard?
明白
Yes.
要是有其他孩子跑来告诉您
And if instead another child ran over to you
说看见她怎么摔的
and told you he saw her fall off the monkey bars,
有人目击 这就是直接证词
that's direct testimony because someone witnessed it.
大家能明白
Does everybody understand that difference,
间接证据和直接证词的区别吗？
between circumstantial evidence and direct testimony?
能
Mhmm.
没有直接证词
Without direct testimony,
就不能肯定犯罪一定发生
we cannot be positively certain a crime has been committed.
作为检方
As the prosecution,
我得把罪证明到排除合理怀疑
I must prove the defendant's guilt beyond a reasonable doubt.
即 从现有的证据中
Meaning, that there is no other reasonable explanation
不存在其他合理解释
that can come from evidence presented.
谁是犯罪受害者
If any of you have been victims of a crime,
请举手
please raise your hand.
费伯先生 您遭遇了什么？
Uh, Mr. Faber, what was the crime?
我被抢劫了 持枪的
Uh, I was robbed. At gunpoint.
您认为
Do you have any reason to believe
那次遭遇会妨碍您
that experience would make you unable to serve
担任此庭公正陪审员吗？
as an impartial juror on this trial?
不会
No.
沃德小姐
Miss Ward.
什么？
What?
刚问到受害者时
When I asked who has been a victim of a crime,
您举手了吧？
did you raise your hand?
不是的 我不能讲这件事 就...
No, I realized I shouldn't share it. So...
不能讲受害经历？
You're unable to share the crime?
这样说吧 大庭广众说出来那事儿
It is frankly my worst nightmare to have to tell this whole room of strangers
是我最害怕的
about the thing that happened to me.
所以...
So...
所以我才把手
that is the reasoning as to why I did not decide
又放下来了
to continue having my hand raised.
见谅
Thank you.
那次遭遇会妨碍您
Do you think the crime would make you unable to serve
担任此庭公正陪审员吗？
as an impartial juror on this case?
问得好 我一直在想这个
That is a good question, and one I've been thinking about.
想出结论了吗？
Have you come to any conclusions?
我觉得 退出陪审团更合适
You know, I think I would be better not being on the jury
做别的事情为社会做贡献
and instead would do better fulfilling a different civic role.
什么别的事情？
And what kind of civic role do you have in mind?
谢谢你问 我是个教授
So, thank you for asking. I am actually a professor,
还没转正 期待早日实现
part-time, hopefully soon full-time,
教书很重要
which, teaching is important work.
教学是很有意义的
I think teaching is important.
有人说教师是最合适的陪审员
Some would say that a teacher makes an ideal juror.
才不是呢 不
Absolutely not, no.
你的问卷表上写着...
On your questionnaire, you wrote...
哦 别 别
Oh, no, no.
我没想到会被当众念出来
I did not know that we would be reading those aloud, so.
“你朋友怎样形容你”
"How would your friends describe you?"
“聪明”被划掉了 改成了个“高”
"Smart." Crossed out, then the word "tall."
要是那遭遇让你有偏见 就会免除你
If the crime you were a victim of makes you biased, we will dismiss you.
说了不会惹上事吧？
Can I get in trouble for telling you?
你是受害者 怎会有事？
Why would you get in trouble if you were the victim?
我不知道
I don't know.
法律有很多不讲理的地方
The law makes no sense in my opinion.
那...
I...
那事我从未公开说过
I haven't said it out loud actually before.
没关系的
Well, that's okay.
你报警了吗？
Did you go to the police?
没有
No.
物证只有个扣子
All I had was a button,
我也不想见他坐牢
and I don't want him to go to jail.
为什么？
Why is that?
他有个孩子
He has a kid.
我希望给他个机会改过
I want him to stop being someone who does that.
要是进了监狱
And if he went to jail,
他就永远被定义成那种人了
he'd just be someone who does that, who's now in jail.
法官阁下 我可以上前吗？
Your honor, may I approach the bench?
安尼丝·沃德 获准离庭
Agnes Ward, you are excused.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
书记员 请传下一位陪审员
Clerk, you may call the next juror.
好 现在叫...
Okay. We'll now call up...
雷克斯·哈伯曼
Rex Haberman.
在吗？
Rex?
暖心三明治的时光
天呐
Oh, my God.
刚才满意吗？
Did you have a good time?
什么？
What?
你满意刚才的那个吗？
Did you like the sex we just had?
嗯嗯
Mhmm.
好
Okay.
太好了
Good.
谢谢你
Thank you.
也谢谢你
安尼丝 你带的讨论课
Agnes, we've gotten incredibly positive feedback
学生反馈非常好
from the students in your discussion section
作为兼职教师你很受欢迎
about your part-time contribution to this university.
不管是现任教师 还是前任 都在夸你
From current faculty, former faculty, it's just all glowing.
- 还有前任？ - 有
- Former faculty? - Yes.
大家都这样形容你...
You've been called, let's see,
乐于助人
helpful,
无微不至
supportive,
还有 出类拔萃
extraordinary.
一直在讨论谁来接手
We know there's been talk about the open spot here
普雷斯顿·德克尔离职后的空位
since Preston left, we haven't...
得找个最合适的接手人
well, we wanted to find the right fit for the program.
很高兴 费尔波特这儿
And we are thrilled to finally offer you
终于要请你做全职教师了
a full-time teaching position here at Fairport.
真的？
Really?
真的 真的
Yes, yes.
系里一致同意的
The department voted unanimously.
哇 我接受
Wow. I accept.
太好了
Terrific.
你来教入门课 二十世纪小说
You'll teach our introductory course, "The Twentieth Century Novel,"
你已经带过几回了
which you've led a few times,
还可以自己开一门选修课
and you'll also create your own elective.
我们很想请你
We would love for you to consider
开一门短篇小说赏析课
teaching a class on the art of the short story
都读过你那论文 写得很吸引人
since we all read your thesis and frankly found that fascinating.
行吧
Okay.
想教别的也行
Or if there's another course you'd rather teach, though.
不 不是 只是...
No, no, it's just I...
发表后我就没碰过它 但我会再看的
I haven't looked at my thesis since I published it, but I will.
看完后给你拟一份教学大纲
I can...I can look through it, and I will create a syllabus for you to look at.
太好了
Wonderful.
我们很高兴你能来任教
We're thrilled to have you.
谢谢
Thank you.
安尼丝 跟你说件事
Agnes, I have to tell you something.
我坠入爱河了
I am in love.
- 真的？ - 是呀 - 天呐
- What? - Yeah! - What!
超级 超级女同的那种爱
And like, super, super gay.
远超咱们想象
Like, gayer than we thought.
哦 哇哦
Oh, wow.
天呐 是那位吗？
Oh, my God. With that person?
- 对 弗兰 - 好
- Yeah. Fran. - Okay.
- 对 - 厉害
- Yeah. - Wow.
做女同又被爱 超幸福吧？
Wow. Okay, are you so happy being gay and in love?
幸福死了 做女同又被爱超棒
Oh, I'm like really, really happy being gay and in love.
天呐 你得见见TA！
Oh, my God, you have to meet them!
好 我绝对想见
Yeah, I totally do. I do.
哦 利迪 你值得永远 永远被爱
You...Oh, Lydie, you deserve to be in love all the time forever.
谢谢你 宝贝
Thank you, babe.
对 对了 我拿到职位了
Well, well... so I got the job.
什么？
What?
我刚转正
I got the full-time position.
天呐
Oh, my God!
真假的？安尼丝
What? Agnes!
真的 但没坠入爱河那么棒
Yeah, well, it's, it's...not as good as being in love.
才不是呢 这超棒的
Yes it is. This is amazing.
太好了
This is great.
我的安尼丝
Agnes.
行吧 也挺棒
Yeah, no, it's good.
真的 真的是你应得的 安尼丝
You really, really earned this, Agnes.
这就是你的办公室了
And here is your office.
有需要随时找我
Let me know if you need anything,
像灯泡坏了这类 随时找我
if a light bulb goes out, anything like that.
- 谢谢你 索菲 - 嗯
- Thanks, Sophie. - Mm.
“当我的身体像活塞般起伏时
"And it struck me, as my automaton knees went up and down
【正在朗读《洛丽塔》第二部第32章】
我才发现对小尤物的内心一无所知
that I simply did not know a thing about my darling's mind
也许她稚嫩的想法背后
and that quite possibly behind the awful, juvenile cliches...
有花园 暮色与城堡的大门
there was in her a garden and a twilight and a palace gate,
那朦胧可爱的心境
dim and adorable regions which happened to be
却对我心门紧闭...”
lucidly and absolutely forbidden..."
沃德教授
Professor Ward.
说
Yes.
抱歉 我觉得这书真很恶心
I'm sorry, but I personally found this book really disgusting.
听男人这么说真宽慰
Well, Jeremy, there's a world in which that's a relief to hear.
那文笔呢？
How did you find the writing itself?
这 这就是矛盾的地方
Well, that's the thing is I...I felt pissed off because I...
我讨厌情节本身
really hated the stuff happening
但又喜欢他的文笔
but I really liked the sort of stuff he was saying.
- 又爱又恨 - 嗯 没事
- So I was pissed. - Mmm, okay.
谁还有同感
Was anyone else feeling that way caught between the form,
被手法和内容搞得矛盾？
the presentation itself, and the content of that presentation?
呃 教授 那女士又来了
Uh, professor... that lady is back
又从小窗往这儿看
looking through the little window thing.
她很执着
She is persistent.
像亨伯特想把洛丽塔永远锁在青春里
Much like Humbert's desire to freeze Lolita in time.
- 说得好 - 好 继续读
- Nice. - Okay. Let's read.
“我常常发现 我们俩生活在一个
"For I often noticed that living as we did,
完全邪恶的世界里”
she and I, in a world of total evil..."
- 听说... - 嗨
- So... - Hi.
利迪订婚了
Lydie got engaged.
嗯
Yeah.
什么时候办婚礼？
When's the wedding?
夏天办
It's in the summer.
- 你喜欢弗兰吗？ - 挺喜欢的
- Do you like Fran? - Oh, yeah. Fran is nice.
有点腼腆 善良 个子还高
Reserved, kind of. Really tall.
你想说什么？
What's happening?
听说你转了正职
So you got the job.
是啊
Yes.
我也想要这职位
I wanted the job.
好
Okay.
- 就不觉得自己做错了吗？ - 有错
- Do you feel bad at all? - Yes.
但不是我 是别人的
But, for other reasons, not because of this.
对你来说顺风顺水
Okay, well, um...just because things come easy to you
不代表你能抢
doesn't mean that you get to take things from people
别人难得的机会
who things don't come easy to.
我活得可不轻松
Things don't come easy to me.
就轻松 大家都喜欢你
Yes they do. Everyone likes you.
- 又聪明又性感 - 谢谢
- You're smart, you're hot. - Thank you.
呃 是有魅力
Ew, not like that.
洛根喜欢你 德文喜欢你
Logan likes you, Devin likes you.
利迪喜欢你
Lydie likes you.
德克尔也喜欢你
Decker likes you.
可你并不喜欢我
Well, you don't like me.
还真是
That's true.
仔细想来
You know, when I think about it,
德克尔其实恨我
I think Decker actually hated me.
他最偏心的就是你 你竟敢这么说
You were his chosen one. That's a completely insane thing to say.
不对 因为当你被喜欢
No. Because when you like someone or, like,
或被尊重时
when you respect someone,
人们会尊重你的意愿
there are some ways people treat you that are one way.
尊重你的感受
Respectful, and like,
把你当成有血有肉 有独立思考的人
you're a person who lives and breathes and thinks for them self.
但也有不顾你感受的人
And then some ways people treat you are not that way,
而那很可恶
and they're bad.
好吧 我和他上过床
All right. Well, um, I fucked him...
结果他连当面
and, uh, he didn't even take the time
给我论文批注都懒得做 所以嘛
to give me in-person notes on my thesis. So...
你跟他睡过？
You fucked him?
对
Yeah.
是你同意的吗？
Did you want that?
同意什么？
Want what?
是你主动的吗？
Was it on purpose?
主动的 咋了
Yes, it was on purpose.
就五分钟 挺一般 我玩过更好的
We had, like, five minute sex. It was just okay. I've had better.
我们打烊了 这儿不能停车
We're closed. You can't park here.
糟了 糟了
Oh, shit. Oh, shit.
对不起 我不该冲你吼
Look, I'm sorry I yelled at you.
我儿子汉克也会这样喘 有时很严重
My kid, Hank, gets these breathing attacks too, real bad sometimes.
我知道你在害怕
I know you're scared,
但你已离开车道了 在车里
but you're off the road, you're in your car,
你很安全
and you're okay.
我来带你呼吸 你跟我学 好吗？
I'm gonna breathe and you breathe with me. Okay?
跟上节奏
You just follow.
好 准备好 吸...
All right? You ready? In...
呼 二 三 四 五
Out... two, three, four, five.
吸...
In...
呼 二 三 四 五
Out... two, three, four, five.
吸...
In...
呼 二 三 四 五
Out... two, three, four, five.
吸 二 三 四 五
In... two, three.
呼 二 三 四 五
Out... Two, three, four, five.
真心说 我平时不这么呼吸 但感觉不错
I gotta be honest, I don't really breathe like that, but it feels good.
还好吧？
You doing okay?
干得好
Good for you.
想吃个三明治吗？
You want a sandwich?
我本想摆这儿几张桌子
I wanted to put tables out here, so,
至少有地方坐着吃
people, you know, wouldn't sit on the ground.
这三明治配得上好地方
It's a good sandwich.
不该坐在
You shouldn't eat a good sandwich
都是鸟屎的地上吃
while you're sitting on the ground where the pigeons shit.
算了
Whatever.
他们说 这停车场和垃圾场共用
But they said, you share a...a parking lot with the guys at the dump.
得那帮人同意
So you gotta ask the guys at the dump.
我才不找你们那帮垃圾！
No fucking way I'm asking the guys at the dump!
你才垃圾呢
Fuck you.
一帮垃圾
Fucking assholes.
真好吃
This is good.
嗯 当然好
Yeah, of course it's good.
没有金刚钻哪敢开个店
You don't have a sandwich shop, you don't make a good sandwich.
辣辣的
Spicy.
意大利进口辣椒 挺贵的
Yeah, calabrian chili, very expensive.
安尼丝
Agnes.
啥？
Huh?
- 叫“安你死”？ - 对
- Agnes? - Yeah.
难听
Ugh.
哎呦 你和那帮人一样坏啊
Whoa, you sound like the mean guys from the dump.
喂 我不同意
Hey! I res... I resent that.
那帮人才是垃圾 我说话直 心不坏
Those guys are assholes. I'm honest, not an asshole.
你有个儿子？
You have a son?
他也是垃圾
He's an asshole.
叫汉克
Hank.
- 汉克嘛... - 难听
- Hank is... - Ugh...
不用跟我解释
You don't have to tell me.
听起来像“憨克”(鹅叫)
Sounds too much like the word honk.
- 你有孩子吗？ - 绝不
- You have kids? - No.
不想要吗？
Want some?
啊 我想象不到自己老了啥样
Uh... Well, I can't really imagine myself old.
你以为我能料到变成这样？
You think I imagined myself like this?
不 说实话
No, believe it or not,
我真没料到自己会变成有嘴的山药
I did not think I would end up looking like a yam with a mouth on it.
现实就这样
But here we are.
该来的总会来
It'll happen to you.
你根本料不到
You won't know what hit you.
我就碰上一桩噩事
Something pretty bad happened to me,
因此才有点不正常呢
so that's probably why I'm acting weird.
有多糟？
How bad?
算很糟吧
I guess really bad.
你自己不觉得糟吗？
You don't know it's bad?
不 我知道那很糟
No, I know it's bad.
只是每次跟人提
But mainly because whenever I tell anyone about it,
他们都大惊小怪
they look really scared for me.
除了我那朋友 但她搬走了
Except for my friend, but she moved away.
我一回想就难受
And then sometimes I feel bad when I think about it,
有时...
because...
会浮现一些瞬间
I remember moments of it,
然后身体会有强烈的
and I can feel in my body
排斥反应
that it was really bad.
有时我完全不去想 挺怪的
But then sometimes I don't think about it, which is weird.
不想就内疚 像背叛那段痛
And I feel guilty when I don't think about it.
刚发生的吗？
Did it just happen?
所以你才喘成那样？
Is that why you were huffing and puffing?
不 是三年...
No, it was three...
是三年多前了
a little over three years ago.
好吧 不算太久
Well, that's not that much time.
严格说 也不短了 但也不太长
I mean, it's a lot of time, but it's not that much time, too.
是啊
Yeah.
你...
Are you...
家里有人陪你吗？
okay in your house?
我有只猫
I have a cat.
那好
Okay.
奥宝 别闹
Olga, what the fuck?
奥宝 抓紧睡觉
Olga, go to bed.
呃 奥宝 你在我床上便便了？
Ugh, Olga, did you shit in my bed?
啊！
Ah!
哦！奥宝 你搞什么啊？
Oh! Olga, what the fuck?
天呐
Oh, my God.
想杀就别留它口气啊
Oh, if you wanted to kill it, you should have just killed it!
好 我这就来 这就来
Okay. I'm coming back. I'm coming back.
马上就来 怎么办 怎么办
It'll be over soon. Okay. Okay.
怎么办 需要什么？得找什么来着？
Okay. What do I need? What am I looking for?
哦！袋子 袋子 找到个袋子
Oh! A bag, a bag! I got a bag!
我来了
I'm coming back!
回来了 我回来了 真对不起
I'm back, I'm back, I'm so sorry.
你还好吗？
Are you okay?
不 不是说你 你快死了
No, no you're not, you're dying.
进袋子
Get in the bag.
快进去
Just go in the bag.
对不起了
I'm sorry.
真对不起了
I'm so sorry.
哦 天呐
Oh, God.
盖文！
Gavin!
安尼丝 没事吧？
Agnes, are you okay?
安尼丝？呃...
Agnes? What...
你还好吗？
Are you okay?
你能来上我吗？
Will you come fuck me?
好
Yes.
等等 我得穿鞋
Wait, wait. I need shoes.
我呃...真得穿鞋
I um... I do need shoes.
等一下
One second.
哦 嘿
Oh, hey.
可以进去小便吗？
Can I pee?
好 来吧
Oh, yeah. Definitely.
我能进去吗？
Can I get in?
哦 进来泡？
Oh, in the bath?
嗯
Yeah.
嗯 行啊
Uh, sure.
我转身换衣
I'm just gonna turn around here.
你别看
Don't mind me.
不用藏着掖着
You don't have to hide it.
现在有点小
It's small right now.
男人就是怪
Men are so weird.
谢了
Thank you.
哦 真好
Oh, that's nice.
水温正合适
It's a good temperature.
谢了
Thank you.
我藏着我的小弟弟 真尴尬
I'm embarrassed that I was hiding my dick.
没事
That's okay.
我也用头发遮着胸呢
I put my hair over my boobs.
的确
So true.
抱歉这浴缸太小
I'm sorry the bathtub is so small.
小吗？
This bathtub?
不 正好
No, it's good.
要不我坐你后面？
What if I sat behind you?
- 为啥？ - 那就...
- Why? - So, uh...
就像被抱住
it could be like a hug.
好
Okay.
-  行吗？ - 行
- Yeah? - Yeah.
等下 我能看看吗？
Oh, wait. Can I look at it?
小弟弟？
At my dick?
嗯
Yeah.
嗯...
Hmm...
真没见过这么软的
I've never seen one that soft.
好啊 十年的噩梦从此开始
Okay, I think that just gave me nightmares for the next decade.
不是啦 只是 很少有人这样软着给你看
No, I mean, you just never get to see them like that.
还是软的好
They're better like this.
好 看完了
Okay, I'm done.
你想要那种大家都有的事情吗？
Do you think you want the stuff that everyone has?
你指什么？
What do you mean?
像是家庭之类的 我也不太懂
Like, uh, family or whatever. I don't know.
你想要吗？
Do you want that stuff?
是和你一起吗？
With you?
不
No.
不 你来回答
No, I mean, it was your question.
嗯 我想要那种事情
Yeah. I want that stuff.
挺好
Nice.
你呢？
Do you?
嗯...
Well...
只想让利迪住近点
You know, probably just to keep Lydie closer...
但我看不见
but I don't see it.
看什么？
See it where?
看不见那种未来
Like, in my head.
我看不见自己变老 看不见有孩子
I don't see myself getting older or having kids.
也看不见自己
I don't see myself.
你会是个好妈妈的
I think you'd be a great mom.
为什么？
Why?
你人很好
You're very nice.
没那么好啦
I'm not that nice.
人们开始都说不要孩子
People always say they don't want a kid,
但想法最终会变
but then things change.
我们想要的事情...
What we want and stuff...
最终会变的
I think it changes.
水凉了
It's too cold.
我觉得挺好的
I think it's nice.
“宝贝”相伴的时光
嗨！耶！
Hi! Yay!
嘿 嘿 嘿
Hey, hey, hey.
- 我想死你了 - 我也想死你了
- I missed you. - I missed you.
我太想你了 天呐
I missed you so much. Oh, my God.
带宝宝来了吗？
Is the baby here?
宝宝来了 宝宝来了
The baby's here. The baby's here.
- 嗨 安尼丝 - 嗨 弗兰
- Hi, Agnes. - Hi, Fran.
嘿 弗兰
Fran.
- 你说？ - 还记得吗？
- Yes? - Remember?
嗯
Yeah.
大日子！
Big day!
当然
Definitely.
来吧 宝贝...
All right, sweetie...
你高兴我们来吗？
So, you're glad you came?
我超 超 超 超高兴的
I'm so, so, so, so glad.
现在懂了 原来生孩子时阴道会炸裂
And now I know what an exploding vagina looks like.
嗯哼
Mhmm.
- 坦白说吧 - 嗯？
- So be honest. - Mhmm.
你喜欢她吗？
Do you like her?
- 我的宝宝？ - 对
- My baby? - Yeah.
喜欢 真太爱我的宝宝了
Yeah. I really like my baby.
那真好
Well, that's really good.
你还喜欢我吧？
And you still like me, right?
废话 安尼丝 你俩我都爱
Yes, Agnes. I love you both.
好
Cool.
- 利迪？ - 在
- Lydie? - Yeah?
- 宝贝 帮我抱下宝宝吧 - 好 回来聊
- Babe, will you grab the baby? - Yeah, of course. One second.
- 嘿 - 嗨
- Hey. - Hi.
- 要我帮忙拿吗？ - 没事 不用
- You need help with the stuff? - No, no, no.
- 好 - 来
- Okay. - Hi.
- 可好呀 - 好
- Hi. - Hi.
这儿真不错
Look at this.
哦 我来拿一个
Oh, let me grab one.
不用 我就爱拎包
No, I love holding them.
那么 你...哦 看
So, are you... oh, yes.
嗨 哇 小脸长得真漂亮
Hi. Wow. She has much more of a face.
嗯嗯
Mhmm.
小怪兽简妮
Little freaky baby Janie.
【简妮更女性 而简更中性 改名表明偏好中性命名】
哦 不叫简妮了 叫简就行
Oh, not Janie. Just doing Jane.
嗨 又见到你啦
Hi, nice to see you again.
哦 哦
Oh, oh.
哦 别怕
Oh, it's okay.
哦 我不是故...
Oh, I didn't...
没关系 这种事常有的
It's okay. It happens all the time.
哦 真的吗
Oh, really, does that happen?
因为我的脸吗？ 呵呵
Is it my face?
因为我的脸吗？
Hello, is it my face?
灯塔游！
Lighthouse day!
灯塔游
Lighthouse day.
弗兰 弗兰 灯塔游！
Fran. Fran. Lighthouse day!
灯塔游
Lighthouse day.
简妮 简妮 灯塔游！
Janie, Janie. Lighthouse day!
她昨晚没怎么睡 你懂的
She actually didn't sleep super well, so.
哦
Oh.
是啊 我们真的 真的筋疲力尽
Yeah, we're really, really fucking tired.
她今天不太适合大活动
Yeah, I don't think she's gonna be in for, like, a big thing today.
说宝宝吗？
The baby?
她只是个小宝宝 应该没问题
Well, she's just a baby, she could do whatever.
其实不见得
I mean, not really.
你们俩去吧 我留下来
But you two go. I will stay here.
真的？行
Oh, really? Okay.
我真想让你也看看
I really wanted you to see it.
宝贝 会有机会的 放心
Babe, I will see it at some point. It's okay.
好吧
Okay.
别
No.
不 你俩都去
No, you two go.
不行 总得有人陪简
No, no, someone has to stay with Jane.
我来
I'll do it.
你确定？
Really?
哦 简比较难伺候
Oh, Jane is actually really particular.
交给我吧
I will do it.
天呐 安尼丝 太谢谢你了
Oh, my God. Agnes, thank you so much.
弗兰 我们自由了！自由了！
Fran, we're free! We're free.
灯塔很浪漫的
The lighthouse is very romantic.
就该你俩去
You two should be there alone together.
再造个宝宝什么的
Make another baby or whatever.
就二十分钟 很快的
Like, twenty minutes, that's it.
问一下 她会不会把我吃了？
One question. What if she kills me?
她不吃人
She's not gonna kill you.
嘿...
Hey...
别抱掉了
Don't drop her.
不会 我抱不掉的
No. I won't drop her.
好...
Okay...
好了
Okay.
好的
谢谢
Thank you.
给你小兔兔
Here you go.
太谢谢了
Thank you.
- 给你 宝贝 - 谢谢
- Here you go, babe. - Thank you.
利迪？
Lydie?
嗯？
Yeah?
我该对她说点啥？
What do I say to her?
宝贝 什么都不用说
Babe, you don't have to say anything.
就二十分钟
Twenty minutes.
嗨
Hi.
我是安尼丝
I'm Agnes.
真神奇 最终你会长成个独立的人
Pretty weird you're gonna be a person someday.
别介意 你现在真有点吓人
No offense, but you look insane right now.
光溜溜 头发很少
Skin and just a small amount of hair.
别担心
Don't worry.
很快会变样的
It won't be like that in a little.
能抱抱你吗？
Is this okay or...
行
All right.
不抱了
I'll put you down.
想要啊 那就再抱起来
Oh. I'll pick you back up.
抱了 抱了 抱了
Okay, okay, okay.
你长得真漂亮
You're so sweet looking.
等你长大后 不管什么想法...
When you grow up, you can tell me whatever.
都可以告诉我 哪怕是个坏念头
Like, if you have a thought and you're like, that's a bad thought,
我很可能也有过 而且更坏
I probably had that same thought but, like, ten times worse.
所以你尽管说
So you can just tell me.
我不会大惊小怪的
I'll never be scared by that.
要是有人对你做了桩噩事...
If someone does something bad to you...
有人借此闲言碎语 冷嘲热讽...
If someone says something scary...
让你想用铅笔 刀之类的东西自尽
If you wanna kill yourself with like a pencil or a knife or whatever,
都可以跟我说
you can just tell me.
我永远不会评头论足 大惊小怪
I'll never tell you you're scaring me.
我只会说 嗯 我知道...
I'll just say, yeah. I know.
事情有时就这样
It's just like that sometimes.
嗯
Yeah.
对不起
I'm sorry
坏事可能会找上你
that bad things are gonna happen to you.
希望不会
I hope they don't.
要是我能阻止 一定要跟我说
If I can ever stop something from being bad, let me know.
坏事不会给你打招呼
But sometimes bad stuff just happens.
所以我有点心疼你
That's why I feel bad for you,
某种程度上
in a way.
你活着却还体会不到
That you're alive and you don't know that yet.
但我还是能静心聆听的
But I can still listen
不会大惊小怪
and not be scared.
这很好
So that's good.
至少是点儿安慰
Or that's something, at least.
对不起, 宝贝
编
剧
兼
导
演
伊娃·维克托
制
片
人
阿黛尔·罗曼斯基
马克·切里亚克
巴里·詹金斯
原创译制
蒙太奇字幕组
字幕贡献者
翻译/时间轴：小p
校对：Lei、novaeye、小p、Hyde
后期：novaeye、Hyde、NickCollect
蒙太奇字幕组
Telegram和IRC交流群：MontageSubs
字幕许可
CC BY-NC-SA 4.0
摄
影
米娅·乔菲·亨利
剪
辑
艾历克斯·奥洛林
兰迪·阿特金斯
配
乐
莉亚·欧阳·鲁斯李（李明德）
主
演
伊娃·维克托
饰
安尼丝
主
演
娜奥米·阿基
饰
闺蜜利迪
主
演
路易斯·坎瑟米
饰
教授德克尔
主
演
凯莉·麦科马克
饰
校友同事娜塔莎
主
演
海蒂安·帕克
饰
法庭律师威尔逊
E. R.·费特迈斯特
饰
利迪配偶弗兰
主
演
卢卡斯·赫奇斯
饰
邻居盖文
主
演
约翰·卡洛·林奇
饰
三明治店老板皮特
对不起,宝贝
A24影业
蒙太奇字幕组 (MontageSubs)
用爱发电 ♥ Powered by love